<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>algorithms - Category - Viraj Shah</title>
        <link>https://viraj071.github.io/categories/algorithms/</link>
        <description>algorithms - Category - Viraj Shah</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>virajshah.77@gmail.com (Viraj Shah)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>virajshah.77@gmail.com (Viraj Shah)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 21:28:20 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://viraj071.github.io/categories/algorithms/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Unique Substrings in Wraparound String</title>
    <link>https://viraj071.github.io/unique-substrings-in-wraparound-string/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 21:28:20 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://viraj071.github.io/unique-substrings-in-wraparound-string/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Solving Unqiue Substrings in Wraparound String problem on Leetcode.
The overall gist of the problem is as follows: Given a string p, you need to find the total count of all the non-empty unique substrings of p, present in a infinite wraparound string of abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz, where length of p could be over 10000 characters.
The brute force solution to this problem would be to go over all the substrings of p and check if they are present in the above wraparound string.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Largest Divisible Subset</title>
    <link>https://viraj071.github.io/largest-divisible-subset/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 20:54:20 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://viraj071.github.io/largest-divisible-subset/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I was solving the problem Largest Divisible Subset on Leetcode a while back.
The problem is as follows:
Given a set of distinct positive integers, we need to find the largest subset of this set such that every pair(E1, E2) of elements in that set satisfy one of the following conditions:
 E1 % E2 == 0 E2 % E1 == 0  If there are multiple such subsets, we can return any one of them.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Wiggle Subsequence</title>
    <link>https://viraj071.github.io/wiggle-subsequence/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 18:57:52 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://viraj071.github.io/wiggle-subsequence/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I was solving a problem called Wiggle Subsequence on leetcode today.
I spent sometime thinking of the solution to the problem before I realized that there was a similar named problem I had solved recently. Longest Increasing Subsequence.
One of the solutions to the problem runs in O(n2) time. That solution calculates the longest increasing subsequence of a given index i by checking the longest increasing subsequence for all indices j &lt; i for which nums[i] &gt; nums[j].]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
